# Masoud Asadzadeh

# C# .NET Backend Developer

Language: English
Nationality: Iran

in LinkedIn

GitHub



#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# 

Backend Developer (2020 (remote))

### Project: Government Service, User Monitoring, and Ticketing

- Contributed to the development of REST APIs on Service Oriented architecture with the focus on connecting the internal government system to on-line interfaces and allowing citizens to transact with government entities to renew their licenses, to pay tax/fines/car tolls/property tolls
- Created backend for single page event log analyzer & ticketing application.

# Backend Developer (2018-2019 (remote)) Project: AutoTaxi (ETAXI)

- Designed and developed workflows and processes for taxi-business to serve taxi companies' needs of metropolitan cities such as buying/selling taxies, issuing driving certificates, school services.
- Participated in the design and development of service oriented architecture to meet the process-oriented business needs.
- Achieved improvement in the system's speed by 50% and enhanced scalability and maintainability.

# Backend Developer (2016–2017)

### **Project: E-Commerce Application (Epardis)**

- Designed and developed backend and database for NopCommerce (open source E-commerce) for booking services such as catering, equipment hire, and car rental.
- Unified the process of document generation and transmission engine by building a set of libraries and interfaces (E-Letters).

## Backend Developer (2014-2017)

#### **Project: Automation of Vehicle Technical Inspection (VTI)**

- Automated the recognition and image processing of vehicles' number plates using C++ open source libs.
- Assisted to record inspection hardware outputs & to issue the certification.
- Established a fully customizable inspection software for users across the country.

# FullStack Developer (2013-2016)

### **Project: Funeral Service Management**

- When I was hired, the FSM Application was scattered into decentralized apps which had massive cost on support, development, and maintenance.
- Achieved, roughly, a 200% improvement in performance by developing a centralized webApp Automating Burial and Funeral Procedure, supporting selling gravesites, custom reports as well as integrating with BI programs.

# 

#### End to End Developer

### Project: Supply Chain Automation - Textile, Home Furnishing

- Developed core functionalities of SCM operations for the management of customer orders, sourcing, logistics, warehouse, and payroll, financial operations, inventory, distribution, etc.
- Exported invoices to MS excel and Crystal reporting service to save time and money by removing paper works.

# **ABOUT**

A software developer with a demonstrated history in the industry who worked on commercial countrywide and corporate IT-type applications, developing and maintaining newly developed and legacy progressive apps utilizing ORD and .NET in a scrum team. Willing to learn who can play a reliable and loyal role in a team.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Languages	Years
C#	••••
TSQL	••••
HTML, JavaScript, CSS	••••
Web Frameworks	
ASP.NET Web Forms	$\bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet$
ASP.NET MVC	••••
.NET Core	••••
<b>Desktop Frameworks</b>	
Windows Forms	$\bullet \bullet \circ \circ \circ$
WPF	••••
<b>Communication Frameworks</b>	
ASP.NET WebAPI/RESTful	$\bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet \circ$
WCF	$\bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet$
ASMX web Service/SOAP	••••
ORM	
Entity Framework	••••
ADO.NET, LINQ	••••
DataBases	
MS SQL Server	$\bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet \circ$
Reporting	
MS SQL Reporting Service	••••
Crystal Reports	••••
Versioning and Build Tools	
TFS, MicrosoftVisualStudio	••••
3rd Party .NET	
DNN (CMS)	••••
NopCommerce (E-commerce)	••••
Server Technologies	
Windows Server, IIS	••••
SDLC	

Agile development/Scrum

Solid principle, DesignPattern

#### FREELANCING PROJECTS

#### Legacy Migration on Real Estate Portfolio Management

Contributed to the migration of MS Access database to SQL Server and Web Form app into MVC.

#### **Automation System of Transportation**

Developed a distributed desktop solution that offers transportation services throughout the country. All orders are logged from the registration time to delivery time using RFID tech.

# Flight Information Display App

Created an application to display real-time flight information for passengers can be used in airports and hotels. It can be connected to online flight information data source and customizable to show Ads.

#### WCF Service front-ended by USSD

Developed a service to issue up to 15-thousands real-time permits a day to control the entrance of vehicles into traffic zones.

#### **Payment Provider**

Worked with POS terminals SDK for developing payment providers.

#### **Facial Navigator Speaker**

Implemented a voice-face recognition prototype for navigation purpose using EmguCV (.NET wrapper for C++ OpenCV computer vision library). Composed of six components: Face Detector, face database, Training Set Manager, Face Recognizer, speaker, Speech Recognizer.

#### **EDUCATION**

B.Sc in Software Engineering University of Science and Culture (2005–2010) 
♥ Tehran, Iran

### **TEACHING ASSISTANT**

Internet engineering, Advanced Object-Oriented Programming

# **PUBLICATION**

Forecasting rail transport petroleum consumption using an integrated model of autocorrelation functions-artificial neural network. Journal of Acta Polytechnica Hungarica, 11(2), 203-214.

#### **SOFT SKILS**

Cooperative, adaptable, enthusiastic about learning, and reliable.

#### **HOBBIES**

Watching Documentaries

Reading A Hiking